# **BOHDAN KUTSENKO**

bohdan.workspace0@gmail.com Warsaw, Poland +48 22 389 6000

#### SUMMARY

Hi there name Bohdan, a Full-Stack ReactJS+TypeScript developer based out of Poland. I have 7+ years of professional experience building a bunch of awesome products right from scratch covering various domains like fin-tech, e-commerce, mergers-acquisition, edu-tech, media, community portals, etc. ranging from early stage startup to well established organizations.

### **TECH STACK -**

Front-End: ReactJS+TypeScript, Apollo-Client, Material-UI, React Testing Library, NextJS, Gatsby,

Angular(v12+), Vue.js

Back-End: NestJS, GraphQL, PostgresQL, MongoDB, Python, Express.js

**Devops**: AWS - EC2, Lambda, S3, DynamoDB, SAM, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Docker

### **EDUCATION**

Lodz University of Technology (Sep. 2013 – Aug. 2017)

**Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science** 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Senior ReactJS+TypeScript Engineer, SIGFIG (Oct. 2021 – Dec.2023)

Worked on the core repository that served as the central repository off of which the bank partner advises, and we cut their specific repositories that contained the modifications/customizations. My major role was to build the complex UI functionality/features in the Core repository that was used across different partners.

- I've done many UI feature development that I think are really applauded by my managers and colleagues. But there's one that I think I'm really proud of is the refactoring of a very complex/large container that contained 2k lines of code and I cut it down to 600 lines. It improved developer experience a lot like it was so much easier to integrate/implement any new feature and get that working within minutes.
- Developed tons of components in ReactJS hooks and TypeScript with apollo-client as an interface to talk to server using GraphQl queries. All the components were covered with their own unit/component test case using react-testing-library.
- There was not even a single piece of text that was hard-coded or we can say, no static text. All of that we pull in
  from the CMS, content-stack using GraphQL queries for each and every text on the application. This was
  just to make sure that every partner can customize according to their needs right from the content-stack User
  Interface instead of digging inside the code.
- Utilized the well-known tech, Storybook, to develop all the Core repository components in an isolated manner
  that covers all the state of the component regardless of how it works inside the application and we can easily
  play around with them on the very organized UI that Storybook provides. Really helpful when there's a huge
  codebase and we've to implement a new feature and for that the small pieces like buttons, cards, etc. are prebuilt and we just have to now plug-n-play.

### Full Stack JavaScript Developer, McKinsey (Dec. 2019 - Sep. 2021)

The project(myIMO) involved building a tool for mergers and acquisitions purposes which contains a number of common features like a config dashboard, client facing application, admin panel. Main role was to tackle problems on the frontend but worked on the backend too.

- Have gone through the whole software development lifecycle, ranging from prototype discussion, business logic, to development and writing test cases.
- Implemented the email service in typescript using AWS SES.
- Setup the front-end architecture of the config dashboard microservice of the application consisting of the react, redux, styled-components, sagas/thunk, cypress, jest/react-testing-library.
- Developed end to end features with backend in typescript/node to react front-end application including creation
  of microservice, deploying docker image, checking deployment and logs on CircleCi and kubernetes
  dashboard.
- Worked on various super cool technologies such as Docker, kubernetes, CircleCi, Typescript, and Postgres
  as DB
- Implemented a couple of UI libraries like **BlueprintJs and ag-grid** enterprise edition for phenomenal grid performance.
- Strong team player and high achiever with demonstrated experience in quickly coming up to speed, meeting project deadlines and exceeding expectations.

### Software Developer, NearGroup (Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019)

NearGroup is a Chatbot with over 15 millions of users having its chatbot on various platforms like Facebook, Twitter, Viber. They also have native apps primarily focused on dating and all sorts of stuff.

- Work includes different phases from API development to pixel perfect User Interfaces.
- Built a tinder-like dating web-app in react(hooks), wrote its APIs in python flask and used mongodb as a database.
- Implemented image prefetching on to the dom, caching mechanism in the apis.
- Maintained the company's overall front-end code which includes 5-6 projects including a full-fledged reactredux PWA.
- Wrote rest APIs in flask for the main app, implemented features such as group video match logic, uploading
  images on s3, login logic, SMS invitation to the contacts using Twilio that are deep-linked to the app.
- Responsibilities included regular client interaction and demos.

# **OTHER KEY PROJECTS (Freelance/Personal)**

# Senior ReactJS Developer, ShopLife (Apr. 2021 – Nov. 2021)

This is a **personalized e-commerce application** containing many features from onboarding the user with all their personal details like height, weight, gender, style preference, etc. and based on that, they prepare the products list accordingly to be shown on the dashboard page. I was the **only front-end developer** here and took the project **from scratch to production**.

- Started the application from line 1 to thousands of lines in production.
- Setup the front-end architecture of the entire app using CRA and followed the container-component pattern.
- Used Bootstrap as the CSS library/framework.

- Good understanding of project life-cycle
- Scoping and requirements gathering
- Hands-on experience on multiple technologies such as react, python, mongodb, Some AWS services s3, cloudfront, ec2, dynamoDB, lambda functions.
- Sound knowledge of GIT and Subversion

# Junior Web Developer/Intern, RedCarpetup (Sep. 2017 – Mar. 2018)

RedCarpet is a VC funded fintech startup lending where banks cannot see.

### SKILLS

- Build the entire UI for the enterprise-level web application of the company from scratch using various tools like bootstrap, jquery, vanilla JS, HTML5, CSS3, flask, etc.
- Developed Restful APIs in python's flask web framework and some in nodejs.
- Developed UI specific features for internal product which is developed in reactjs.
- Built the company's main website in gatsbyjs(which is on top of reactjs) and graphql using GraphCMS as headless CMS.

## Shill Dates Webapp, ShillDates (Apr. 2018)

### SKILLS

- Tech stack: React on front-end, firebase's firestore to pull data from, a couple of nodejs apis deployed on firebase cloud functions.
- Used chartjs library for data visualization, node-mailer for sending mails and reCaptcha v2 for captcha verification.
- Previously used GraphCMS with graphql query on front-end in place of firebase but replaced due to cost.
- Converted the given data from excel sheets to valid json file(data normalization), handled diacritics issue, uploaded it to firebase in the required format.
- Deployed on netlify with continuous deployment.

### **MINOR PROJECTS**

# Web Scraping Project (Jul. 2018)

**Scraped** through the multi page website using **python's Beautiful Soup package**, and wrote the logic from extracting the required data, writing it to excel file, handling all edge cases like unicode characters and some non-uniform data.

# JobMate Chrome Extension (Jan. 2019)

Built a chrome extension that pops in as soon as you open a job portal such as Linkedin, and a button will appear on click of which an auto-filled(background scraping performed) form appears. Basically the idea was to gather the data in appropriate format according to the business needs.